#### Lisa Michelle Hill

lisahill207@gmail.com (703) 309-7033 www.lisahill.dev linkedin.com/in/lisa-m-hill

#### **Objective**

After 9 years as a higher education professional, I am following my passion for technology. Combining my professional experiences in program management and customer success with skills from my recent B.S. in Web & Digital Design, I am seeking employment as a Front-End Developer.

#### **Education**

# B.S., Web & Digital Design University of Maryland Global Campus

## M.Ed., Student Personnel in Higher Education. University of Florida

## **B.A., Humanities, Science and Environment**Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University

#### **Technical Skills**

#### Languages

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript (ES14)

#### **Professional Experience**

## Towson University - Academic Advising, Retention, and Completion Office Academic Advisor for Transferring and First-Year Students

2019 – Present

2016

- Hire, train, and supervise 8 student academic advisor undergraduate student employees.
- Promote academic success by advising 40 first-year freshmen in one-to-one, small group, large group, and online settings.
- Increase retention by providing interventions and support for students on academic alert, academic warning, and academic probation.
- Strengthen campus partnerships by liaising and networking with faculty and staff advisors in the College of Liberal Arts.
- Improve the transfer experience by providing appropriate and effective academic advising to students from the pre-admissions process, through post-matriculation.

## **Towson University - Office of Civic Engagement & Social Responsibility Coordinator of Community Service**

2017 - 2019

- Hire, train, and supervise one graduate assistant and 7 undergraduate employees.
- Advise Alternative Break Connections (ABC) student organization leadership board, including managing \$40,000 operating budget and providing on-call assistance for all domestic and international student travel.
- Promote mutually beneficial programming and maintain partnerships with over 60 regional nonprofits.

#### Lisa Michelle Hill

lisahill207@gmail.com (703) 309-7033 www.lisahill.dev linkedin.com/in/lisa-m-hill

- Plan and implement weeklong volunteer, experiential, and educational programming as part of Hunger & Homelessness Awareness Week, and National Volunteer Week.
- Manage transportation funding and logistics for BTU, a presidential initiative to promote partnerships between Towson University and the greater Baltimore region.

### Virginia Tech - VT Engage: The Community Learning Collaborative Interim Service Learning Coordinator

2016-2017

- Develop curriculum and facilitate weekly trainings for STEP UP student leaders on topics including reflection, facilitation, group development process, and social issue education.
- Create materials and procedures for integrating learning outcomes and enhanced educational programming into student led immersion programs.
- Partner with campus departments and faculty members to create meaningful community engagement experiences.

#### **Volunteer Experience**

#### Co-Leader, Girl Scout of Central Maryland Council

2017 - 2020

- Plan and facilitate badge activities for troop of 10 girls.
- Mentor scouts both as part of Girl Scouts and outside of troop activities.